chopra.com 2015-12-18

# Privacy Policy | The Chopra Center

## Our Commitment to Privacy

The Chopra Center ("we," "us" or "our") respects your privacy. We collect user information in an effort to improve your experience and to communicate with you about our products and services. This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of companies that we do not own or control, or to people whom we do not employ or manage. We do not sell or rent your personal information to third parties.

This Privacy Policy describes the personal information we collect about you, why we collect it, and how we use it. Our Privacy Policy also describes the choices you can make about how we collect and use your information. If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy, you can always contact The Chopra Center in any of three ways:

 ** **S** end us an e-mail** : [chopracenter@chopra.com](mailto:chopracenter@chopra.com)

 ** **C** all us at**: 1-888-434-6772 or

 ** **W** rite to us at:**  
The Chopra Center  
6451 El Camino Real Suite A  
Carlsbad, CA 92009  
Attention: Customer Service Privacy Policy

If our Privacy Policy information practices change in the future, we will post an updated Privacy Policy on our website. You can tell if the Privacy Policy has changed by checking the revision date that appears at the end of this Privacy Policy. You may exercise your choices about how we collect and use your information at any time.

## What kind of information does Chopra collect?

We collect information, such as name, e-mail and postal addresses, phone number(s), birth date or age, gender, occupation, industry and personal interests from you when you visit our website, save your information with us online, visit the website of our marketing partners or participate in a contest, promotion or survey. We maintain a record of your interests and the services and features you use, and may also acquire information about you from our marketing partners, from unrelated third parties, and from our affiliates.

## How does The Chopra Center use my information?

We will use your e-mail and postal address to send you information about Deepak Chopra and Chopra Center events and products, and our affiliates' products, services, contests, and promotions and to help us learn more about your user preferences. If you participate in a contest or promotion (online or over the phone), we may use your personal information to send you e-mails, postal mail, or telephone (including text messages) regarding our services, contests and promotions. From time to time, we may use this information to contact you via e-mail, postal mail, or telephone to learn more about your user preferences. You always have the choice to unsubscribe and not to receive marketing information or calls.

In addition, we may use information about you and your interests from us and our affiliates to help us improve our site design and your online experiences. We may contact you, subject to the choices you have made, via e-mail, postal mail, or telephone, to conduct market research and learn more about how we can improve our service offerings.

## Does the Chopra Center share my information with third parties?

The Chopra Center never shares your information with third parties. 

When we offer products, services. contests and promotions, with or without a marketing partner, you may be required to provide certain personal information in order to participate. In these cases, we will give you the choice not to receive e-mail messages or other communications from us regarding our services, contests, and promotions. In this case, however, The Chopra Center may still need to contact you, for example, to notify winners and to fulfill promotional obligations.

If some or all of our business is sold, The Chopra Center will disclose your personal information to a purchaser that agrees to abide by the terms and conditions of our Privacy Policy.

The Chopra Center reserves the right to disclose information about you as required by law, in response to legal process and law enforcement requests, and as necessary to protect the property, interests and rights of The Chopra Center, its affiliates, and others.

## How do I access my information? How do I change or delete my information?

You may manage your information and email subcription preferences at any time by visiting [http://www.subscription.chopra.com](http://www.subscription.chopra.com/) and updating your profile. Your requested changes will take effect immediately. 

## How does The Chopra Center protect kids' privacy?

Chopra is concerned about the safety of children when they use the Internet and will never knowingly request personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13.

## What are cookies? How does The Chopra Center use cookies on its site?

A cookie is a small data file that websites often store on your computer's hard drive when you visit their sites. A cookie may contain information, such as a unique user ID that websites use to track the pages of the sites you've visited. We use cookies in order to recognize you as a registered user and to improve your experience. We also use cookies to identify whether you visited one of our affiliates' websites immediately prior to visiting our website.

You can refuse cookies by turning them off in your browser. If you turn off cookies, though, we will not be able to recognize you as a registered user, which allows you to access your account information.

## Is my information secure?

We sell products and services on our website and accept credit card or financial information from you. We use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology or another encryption technology to protect your online order information as it is transmitted over the Internet and we will update our Privacy Policy.

## What about links to other websites and services?

The Chopra website may contain links to other sites, including to our marketing partners. The Chopra Center does not control the privacy policies or practices of these websites. You should review those policies before providing any personal information. Chopra is not responsible for the content or practices of any linked websites, and we provide these links solely for the convenience and information of our visitors.

## TRUSTe

The Chopra Center is TRUSTe-certified. If you believe that your inquiry has not been addressed to your satisfaction, you should contact TRUSTe, which is an independent privacy organization. TRUSTe will act as a liaison with Chopra to resolve your concern.

Rev 7_2013
